Hello
This is my message for millennials
On how to change the world
Rather, I would say, "How to change the world right."
Of course the next question will be what do you mean by saying it correctly
And certainly this is the main issue
So I'll talk about that briefly
I will also offer a suggestion
Every millennial is ready to watch this
The reason for raising this topic was
Before something I read recently
By Jonathan Haidt
Jonathan Haidt is a professor of ethical leadership
In New York University for a rigorous business education
He was a clever commentator at the last time
About some political conflicts
That occurs in the social sciences
By note for example
That there is a dearth of political diversity in viewpoints in the social sciences and perhaps even less
By people specializing in the humanities
And Haidt recently wrote something
I will link to it in the description of the video
And in it he claimed that universities have to make up their minds
Between social justice and truth
And at the tip of the truth put
Philosopher John Stuart Mill
The English philosopher who said:
"He who knows only his side of the case
Little is known about this issue
May his arguments be good
No one can refute it
But if he is not equally able to refute the arguments against him on the other side
And if he does not do much to find out who they are
It has no basis for preferring any opinion. "
And after that
In comparison, he put John Stuart next to Karl Marx.
Who said, "Philosophers only interpreted the world in different ways the aim was to change it."
Marx was considered the saintly leader
For the University of Social Justice
Which is geared towards changing the world
By overthrowing the structures of power and privilege
It sees political diversity as a hindrance
Mel, on the other hand, according to Haidt.
He is the Saint Commander
What is called the University of Truth
Which sees reality as a process
It pushes people to test each other's biases and incomplete logic, and through this process everyone gets smarter
"Haidt" indicates that the University of Truth dies when it is ideologically united or politically intolerant
I think this video is part of my claim on Jonathan Haidt's side.
For youth to join "Truth University"
But there is a problem with that
Because the university is the place to search the truth
This is the basis of the university
But there is a problem, which is that young people want to change the world
He is part of what Piguet calls the developmental psychologist
Piguet calls it the "stage of Christ."
And there is some benefit from that
Because we are social beings
While we are building ourselves
And while we shape ourselves
And we bring our personalities into existence
Based on our biological strength. On our biological existence
We also have to, in return, integrate and adapt
We adapt to merge with the negotiation with the community
And according to which sometimes has to change
The structure of society must be preserved
But it must be updated and improved as it progresses
Therefore the problem is how to update and improve it
Without doing it in a quick way
So that you destroy everything valuable
So the problem that I find in the Marxist perspective
And I have this problem with him for a long time
I don't think you should trust people who are their primary target
When they try to change the world for the better, by changing other people
And you can know these people because they always blame others
And they are looking for victims
They are looking for perpetrators and victims
Then they proceed to stop the perpetrators
And I think that is wrong
Because, as he said, "Alexander Solzhenitsyn" is a great Russian writer
He helped overthrow the Soviet Union
He said, "The line between good and evil runs in the heart of every person."
So the basic battle
According to what I think
This falls within the tradition that put "John Stuart Mill."
It is "to overcome tyranny and hatred."
Anarchy, nihilism, desire and urging everything to stop
You have to repair the gaps
And cracks
In your soul, simply
And that means you have to face
The evil that inhabits your heart
A statement from the New Testament
Which in my opinion fits with this idea
This is part of "Sermon on the Mount."
It is a central text in the Western tradition
And clearly the central text of Christianity
But it is central to everything built by Western civilization
And in it, Christ addresses his followers
Why are you looking at the moth?
Which is in your brother's eye
As for the plank in your eyes, do not notice it?
Or how do you say to your brother;
Let me get the speck out of your eye
And here is the wood in your eye?
You hypocrite, first get the plank out of your eye
And at that time you will see well to get the speck out of your brother's eye
I like this quote
Because he places the responsibility
For a change in every stage of existence
On the individual
It is clear that the individual interacts with society
But the idea is here
Unless the individual did
Straighten his soul
There is no possibility of impact
Which the individual will leave on society
Only to be something other than harmful
The same amount of harm that still exists in the soul
These are important things to know
These are very important things to know
But then we face the conundrum that young people, too, want to change the world
But this is not a problem
Because I think you can
Bring the "University of Truth" alike with desire
To make a real change
But change has to start from the right start
So I'll tell you how I think
You have to change yourselves in order to change the world
And so the world that you bring into being is the best, not the worst
Remember
You have to know this
The world that Marx’s followers brought into existence in the twentieth century
More than a hundred million people were killed
In China and Russia
I mean the Soviet Union and regions like Cambodia and Vietnam
Of course the world has changed as a result of the Marxist dogma
But he did not change in the good path
And, of course, the Marxist faith
It makes itself heard
In a colossal way
Again across the west now
So what do you have to do about it?
Take this idea
The first thing you have to do is direct yourself
Most of you have probably seen the movie "Pinocchio."
And "Pinocchio" is about a doll
Its strands are attracted by forces outside of its absorption
This is the position of the immature individual
Gibto is a good father
It represents the symbol of good, "the symbol of a beneficial / good civilization."
He makes a doll to be his son
And then he makes a wish from the star
A star is something that shines in the sky
It is linked to the transcendent, the backward and the divine
If you look at the sky at night
The place was very dark
You feel dread
Because you face your souls
So to speak, "your individual soul faces the universe."
And you can feel the relationship
Between you and
the college
So looking at the sky
It is more like a religious experience
If a sky is full of stars
He asked for a wish from the star
It is finding the light that guides you
As the North Star
Let us seek the ultimate goal
To seek the ultimate goal that you can imagine
This is what Gpeto does.
He raises his eyes
About his daily concerns
He tries to establish a relationship
With the highest possible values
It also has the deepest wishes
And the most deepest wishes
Is that the doll he made
You may turn out to be a real individual
Real and complete as a mature human
This is what you can wish for yourself
You can wish
And seek it in yourself
This way you deal with suffering
That are present in life
Because life is suffering
And because life is very difficult
People may get sick
And they become mentally ill
And there is malice in the world
And there are misfortunes
This is why life is very, very difficult
If it is not oriented correctly
With regard to life
The fact that it is difficult
And it is full of suffering
Because that may divert you, woe and tie you
Until you become a thug
And malevolent
And it may become more than shedding and hatred
To wish massacres
And even that you wish everything destroyed
Therefore, you must learn to strengthen yourself as an individual so that you can bear the burden of existence without being corrupt
You have to decide that this is what you are seeking
You want to be a fully fledged human being
And you stop being a pathetic doll
Their leads are attracted by terrible forces behind the scenes
To wish the star
It is to strive for the supreme good
The question then is
What is good?
We can answer this in two ways
We can say that good is the opposite of evil
And I can tell you what evil is
Evil is the conscious desire to achieve suffering
When suffering is not necessary
If you read about what happened
In the Nazi concentration camps
For example
Or in Russian concentration camps in the Soviet Union
You will find what helps you about what constitutes evil
Evil is the desire to take advantage of the weakness of others
To take advantage of others' weaknesses with self-awareness
And to escalate their suffering beyond their endurance
So the good is the opposite
Whatever the opposite
Goodness blinds its explanation
But here is one hint
And I understood this by reading "John Piguet"
Developmental Psychologist
Piguet spoke of the "standard phase."
The "standard stage" is like a game that children play
And in it every child wants to play the game
You have a small social group and this is the children's play group
And the individuals who are in it
These are individual children
And structure is the game
And it's a good game if everyone wants to play it
Bigger is not lucky to have a game like this
You will beat a game that tyrannizes people to play
Because it does not entail a forced application of costs
So the idea of ​​the "standard stage" was developed.
To think that
If you seek good
You want what is best for you
And I mean fine to you as if you are taking care of yourself
Or treat yourself like someone you love
Which will be good for you and your family too
Which in turn will be good for you, for your family, and for the community
So it will be good for you, for your family, for society, and then for the world
Then it will be good for now
Then it will be okay for next week
And the week after that
And a year from now
And even the future as you can see
So the goodness is something that balances out
Between multiple stages of existence
In multiple time frames at the same time
You don't have to know
What will happen from this at any moment
But you can direct yourself
That this is the state you want to be in
And I can tell you
As far as I can tell
When in this state
Even if moment by moment
Your life is saturated with a sense of meaning
This sense of meaning
It helps you to stand up from the suffering
The philosopher "Nietzsche" says:
"A person who lives for a purpose can endure anyway."
So the idea of ​​"Nietzsche" was
If there is a purpose for your life
Nobly enough
It's not just that suffering in life is acceptable
But it may also be commendable
You may be ready to bear the burden of existence
Because of the exciting things you can do with existence
Things that you can build and achieve
This may be the highest imaginative state of existence
This is a form of paradise
But it is not the paradise that you attain by changing others
But it is the paradise that you attain
By changing yourself
This is a difficult thing to do
It's scary to do
Because it means
That you are reshaping your soul
This is a task for someone who is truly honest and noble
It's interesting enough
To keep you occupied for the rest of your life
And then magic things will happen to you
While doing it
And the world will be around you
In a more amazing way
Musically
So that every part of what you live
He plays against every other part
In a way that is deeply meaningful from every aspect in it
By the way, you are experiencing that
When you listen to a piece of music you love
Music represents that
Because music nourishes the soul
And because it is the highest form of art
At least from my point of view
So you have to live your life
As if
Existence is a symphony
And you are playing the part of your track
Once you direct yourself
So you have commitment
A commitment to developing your soul
To speak the truth
However, you have to be properly oriented
Because the truth
Something exists as an interest for an ideal
Like a top of sorts
Then you can imagine that you are using your language in two ways
You can use your language to manipulate the world
And get what you want from it
As an example
Maybe go out on a date with someone
It was decided that the final goal of it was the date
Is that you get a partner to have sex tonight
Then you can configure your language
To influence the person until he saves you
What you want
This is a manual use of language
But
The problem is that
There are several problems with that
But one of them is
What if your idea of ​​what to seek is wrong?
Perhaps that is not the way it should be treated
The person you are on a date with
Maybe you reduce or decrease
The interactions between you
Than it may be
health condition
And thin
Of interaction and dialogue
To something
Simply the pursuit of impulsive pleasures
And maybe that is not good for you
For the next week and the next
And next month
Directing yourself to impulsive pleasures can be a very bad idea
Remember what happened in Pinocchio.
Pinocchio goes to the island of pleasures
And the island of pleasures is a place where he gets impulsive pleasures at the same moment
But what Pinocchio discovers with Jimny, the night cockroach
That the island of pleasure is governed by two masked tyrants
They all wear black
All of you remember that they are transforming the kids and teens on the island of Pleasure
They deny them their voices by turning them into the minds of donkeys
And preparing to sell them as slaves to the salt mines
So there is an implication in the story that the pursuit of impulsive pleasures
It is one of the paths of totalitarianism and slavery
And I believe in that
So the possibility of directing your language towards the attainment of impulsive pleasures
It is a misuse of your highest gift
The gift of slogans, the gift of communication
The alternative is to direct yourself to the ultimate good, as we explained earlier
And then speak the truth
You can know that you are doing it or you can know that you are not
Because if you are not speaking the truth
And you were using someone else's words
You are being deceived by meaning by behind-the-scenes forces
You don't use your own words
You are the puppet of an ideology, another thinker, or of your impulsive desires
And you can know when you speak that
Because it makes you feel weak and ashamed
And you can determine this feeling physiologically
If you listen to yourself while you speak
You can know when you speak the right way that you will experience a feeling of inclusion and strength
And when you speak in a misleading or manipulative way
Feel like you are falling apart in layers
What you need to do is practice only saying the things that make you feel stronger
This will mean from the start that you will notice that most of what you are saying is a lie
It is either a lie or someone else's words
It is very difficult to find your own words, but you do not really exist until you find your own
Then you try to teach yourself how to speak your own truth
You listen to other people while you do this
Because they can help you shape and correct your words
They will react poorly to it if your thoughts are poorly worded
If you listen and pay attention then you will know how to formulate your words
In a more clear and accurate way
And that makes you more powerful
It gives you more power which is one of the benefits of forms of strength
So you do it and then you have to make the decision to believe
And that is simply either to use your language to manipulate the world and make it achieve what you want
Or, use your language to try to pronounce the truth as carefully as possible
Then you can see what is happening
You have to give up your desire for the sake of the consequences you want
You have to assume that if he talks to you the truth
The results are the best possible under the circumstances
It's an exciting way to live in a sense
It's like walking down a cliff because you don't know what will happen next
If all you do is say what you think
You might be at work, say what you think, and then get fired
Then she says, "Oh my God what a terrible misfortune."
But maybe it's not like that because maybe if you worked in a place and you had to lie in order to keep your job
You probably shouldn't be there
Maybe your soul will die and destroy you
Permanently and make you spoiled
Therefore, you must guide yourself and speak the truth as carefully as you can
You have to listen to others in order to correct your speech
Then you have to allow the consequences to unfold as they are
This is the ultimate act of faith
This is what you do if you belong to the "University of Truth."
With a more practical speech, then you have to educate yourself
And that's not easy work now
Because you have to find people who can really tell you what to read
And maybe also how to write because writing is a way of expressing your thoughts more precisely
That's why you go to college to learn how to write
If you know how to write then you will be able to think
If you can think, speak and communicate write
Then you are incredibly powerful
According to the authority level
Because the arguments are moving the world forward
If your arguments are coherent, well-structured, clear, and well-adjusted
And analyzed carefully
And you have five displays of logic for everything you do
This is what will happen if you learn how to write correctly
Then you are a force of nature, man
No one can defeat you
This is one of the things that are not taught to people
Why go to learn, especially in the humanities
Teaching "humanities" if real, organizes the basics of your mind
He drops you to the ground, puts you on a rock, and makes you a strength to fight
But you have to read for the right people
These are the great people of the past on my list
These are the greatest men of the past, and that's it
I suggested these and made two lists to read on "Jordanbpeterson.com".
And the people whose books I suggested in the first place were written before
Fyodor Dostoyevsky, Leo Tolstoy who, in my opinion, is the greatest novelist the world has known
Alexander Solzhenitsyn is another great Russian novelist, and I don’t know what the Russians’s story is about, but man, they are producing a book like no other.
Alexander Solzhenitsyn wrote a book called "The Gulag Archipelago" in which he analyzed the Soviet prison system of detention centers that emerged after the Leninist revolution in the second century of the twentieth century.
He detailed, with great precision, how the Marxist principles that had to liberate everyone and change the world
It produced legislation that was completely deadly in its consequences
Solzhenitsyn carefully traces the logical path from original Marxist principles to legislation and even genocide.
Because you will hear people who are simply Marxists who will say something like "True Marxism did not exist" and "Solzhenitsyn" made this argument separately in the mid-1970s.
And the "Gulag Archipelago" was an ideological bomb that destroyed all the credibility of Marxism for intellectual respect.
You have to read the book. The book contains the central problem that is in our culture today. If you do not read it, you are not informed and you can only participate in the discussion as a doll.
So I will not suggest participating in the discussion as a puppet because you do not know behind the scenes and he pulls strings if you remember the story of "Pinocchio"
The forces that were pulling the strings were not forces working in the best interest of "Pinocchio". This is for sure
Guruj Uriel is an English essay writer and unparalleled commentator on socialist totalitarianism even though he is a leftist and an innovator.
Aldous Huxley wrote "Brave New World" and I have wonderful things to say about the potential devastation of sexual choice and sexual partner selection as part of a dystopian future.
Friedrich Nietzsche is a philosopher who describes himself as a person who thought of a hammer, and Nietzsche is a very, very dangerous person, and a really clever writer.
And Karl Jung, who was a student of Nietzsche, and Nietzsche is the philosopher who announced the death of God earlier in the late 1800's, and Jung spent his entire life trying to resurrect the Lord, and this is one way of thinking about it
Educate yourself This is a good way to start. If you are reading these authors then you will know what to read as well
If you read to these authors it will take you a long time and it will be very, very difficult for you
And you will not be the same person when you get out of it and this is very, very terrifying to be torn and rebuilt is not a joke, but it strongly overcomes the alternative.
Which just means being sluggish and being a sluggish baby is something I wouldn't recommend
Nothing is worse than a stagnant forty baby
So that's just the equivalent of your information to Pinocchio. We go back to the story of Pinocchio when he saves Gibto from the underworld.
You remember when he was turned into a half-donkey after he was on "The Island of Pleasure," he was seduced by two people, the fox and the cat.
And those who tried to seduce him into believing that he was a victim and that he needed leave
Therefore, "Pinocchio" was seduced to "The Island of Pleasures" by two characters who played with his victim feeling, his nerves and his suffering to convince him that he should not bear any responsibility for his existence.
And that he can occupy himself with his impulsive pleasures, and in this way he fell into the hands of tyrants on the "island of pleasures."
However, after Pinocchio left the Island of Pleasure, he had to head to the beach twice
The second time he headed to the beach, he was looking for his father
A father to anyone, according to the mythical perspective, dies in the underworld in chaos because everyone inherits a sick and ancient civilization, so to speak.
It is sick and old because it was formed by the dead and the living must resurrect it continuously until it becomes a controlling force
And the living have to resurrect their connection with civilization internally as well, because your structure is from civilization, even though not only the structures of civilization
You have to understand history, otherwise you will not understand yourself, for you are a historical being
So you have to save your dead father from the belly of the beast from the dragon
Because if you remember that the whale in "Pinocchio" is also a fire-breathing dragon
This means that you have to face your most feared fear and when you do then you will save your father from the underworld
These are very complex ideas, and you can read about them in my book, "Maps of Meaning". If you want in the reading list, put a free copy, you can on the "Jordanbpeterson.com" website, where I talk in detail about these matters.
However, you have to resurrect your father before you can be real
This is one of the problems with feminism and the social justice fighter by their insistence on the existence of a patriarchal society
Everyone knows since the beginning of history that civilization is corrupt and tyrannical, but at the same time it is protective and beneficial
Even the language you use is part of civilization. You do not bring down patriarchal society, but revive your civilization
And you do this by taking responsibility for your own existence and then acting as a moral agent in civilization
This is what you do to become an educated person. Read these books, they will change your life. I guarantee that they will change your life.
They will destroy you, destroy you, and then rebuild you for something higher than you are now
Harry, you are in pain.
do not worry
Jenny, you need to find a way out
Follow the hall and you will find Ron
You are a genius, Foxes
I wasn't just fast enough
Sure
Phoenix tears have healing powers
Thank you
It's all right, Jenny
This is what it seeks
This will help
Colleagues and I have developed a series of online writing programs entitled "The Self authring sweet".
It helps people to write about, organize, and understand their past and present personality
Then the Future and the Future Composition Program asks you to write about six different dimensions of your life
So he asks you first to treat yourself as someone you want to help, someone you love and care about, and someone you want to help
Then he asks if you can organize your life in the best possible way
Along with the principles we discussed earlier
what do you want? What do you want for your profession?
What do you really want?
What will make your life valuable? What do you want for your profession?
What do you want for your family? And from your family? What do you want from an intimate relationship?
How will you take care of your physical and mental health? How will you deal with the use of alcohol and drugs?
It asks you a series of basic questions like these
To move your mind
Then he asks you to write for 15 minutes about what your life might be like in three or five years into the future
If it results as if you are drawing the life of someone you deeply care about, then you are required to write about it for 15 minutes without worrying about the structure of the argument or any grammatical checks.
That postpones until later
So it gives you a simple paradise to strive for
Like saying, "Well if I can have that then my life will be worth the trouble, even if I have to struggle for a reasonable time along the way."
This is what you are trying to build, and you can think of it as a paradise worth moving towards
The second part of the program asks you to write about what your life could be like in the next three to five years if all of your bad habits and nihilistic tendencies were.
And your tendencies towards resentment and loss of desire to take responsibility if all your weaknesses take control and knock you down
And everyone knows that.You know what it would be like if you let everything slip and know what hell you'd be headed towards
So the second part of the program asks you to write about what your life might be like over the next three to five years if everything around you ended up in hell.
So it gives you a hell to avoid and a paradise to look towards
And you need both because that is what keeps you properly motivated in life
Then, the second half of the program, which represents the next section of the program, helps you transform your vision for the desired future into an achievable reality.
And its word complementarity and the pronunciation of arguments for why you want it
It also helps you overcome your own doubts because you don't have to argue against other people only
It means arguing against the gossip of the demons of nihilism, despair, and ideological monarchy that exist within your mind and society at the same time.
You need powerful weapons to fight against them
And here is this offer. We have made a free "future authoring program" available for the next period. I don't know how long the period will be, but let's assume a week or something like that.
If you go to ((the address is written in the picture))
You can read about the program there, and now I have to tell you that we have used this program on about 5,000 university students, most of them in the Netherlands but some in Canada as well.
And what we showed is that if you complete the program, even if you do it badly, and I advise, "Do it badly, man" it doesn't matter that you do it in an excellent way.
Do it badly and maybe later you can do better as you progress, but at least it does badly
This program increases the performance of university students, increases their grades between 20 to 25 percent and reduces their withdrawal from studies by the same percentage.
So we have a statistic of 5,000 people and one of these articles has been published and I will link to it in the description of the video
So this program really works if you use it so I highly recommend that you do so
In any case, you can read about this program from there and click on buy for 14.95 and then enter this code (changeyouself) * Note that this may be for the offer now ending
This is what millennials have to do if they want to change the world
The first thing they have to do is direct themselves to do good, and this is away from evil, away from hatred, away from vain, pretended suffering, and pain.
Or rather let us say far from Auschwitz * a Nazi internment camp in Poland * and away from the "Gulag Archipelago" and the heinous Soviet concentration camps and the mass murder that took place in China
So you want to get as far away from it as possible as you can
Any direction away from that is a good trend
After that, you should think about the highest possible good that may appear to you, your family, and your community, as we have already discussed that
Then you have to speak the truth as related to that
Then you have to educate yourself
After that, you have to assume your responsibility, and responsibility is good because it makes you strong under its weight, it makes you strong and enables you to free yourself from your strings.
Turn yourself into an honest individual, and then take on the world
And then you're in a position to make a change
As a person like this, your pure existence will change the world in a positive direction
This is what you should strive for: Read the books that I have posted on my site. Create a "Creating the Future" program, and this will improve your life greatly
In this way, you can change the world